You saw me use PIP to install requests in introduction to Python.
That all happened very fast, and I didn't really talk about where I might go to find out
more information about the request package that I use.
So PIPI, PIPI lives at PIPI.org, and you can find install published Python packages
with this Python package index.
So here I could search for requests, and as of right now, there are 172,000 projects
stored in PIPI.
So I can search for requests, and we'll see a few things here.
Looks like request 3 is a name squad.
That's why they put that there.
So this is in quite the package that we're looking for.
Let's look at this one, and this is a version number.
Here we go, it gives us a project description.
So it's the non-GMO HTTP library for easier HTTP consumption.
And we can look at the release history, we can download the files.
The project will usually have a link at the home page.
We can click here to view the statistics for this, and it's like this is a specific version.
But these two, as statistics right here, we'll see who the maintainers are on the left
hand side, what the license is, the development status, if it's just beta version, and
which versions it supports.
And this is a really, really great tool, a great resource.
You can search for all sorts of external packages here, and to install this library, it
will give you set up instructions right here.
So the new, you'll see PIP being used here, but the new recommended way of installing
packages.
I know I'm going to exit out of my repel.
So I would say don't do this because, as we talked about, as you install more versions
of Python on your system, you'll usually have a Python 2 and a Python 3.
You end up with multiple versions of PIP, and if you don't use the right one or depending
on your system set up, you can install your external libraries to the wrong playus using
the wrong path.
So the safest way of doing this is to be in your virtual environment, and then you just
know exactly where Python points, right, if I say Python dash version here, I know that
it's my Python 3, 7, 2 from my environment because it's activated.
So the better way of doing this is to say Python dash M, which means Python run this as
a module, and give the name of the module as PIP, and then you can say install requests.
This way you're guaranteed to have the right path.
And when you're first starting out or actually just in general, it's important to know
your packages.
So there are a lot of packages on PIPI, sometimes they're not up to date, a good way
of checking, we'll see here, we can look at the product homepage, by the way, that
PIP install is right here, and let's actually look at the base requests.
That's the one that we've been using, this is the base version.
You'll see when it was last released, so the package was last released in 2016, chances
are that this probably not very popular.
Let me see if the statistics for this library, here we go.
So if you click on this, the libraries.io link, you should see some helpful information here.
So I'll show you how many dependencies it has, it'll show you how many dependent packages
there are in dependent repository, so 124,000 projects on GitHub use the library.
It's one of the most popular in Python, if not the most.
37 and a half thousand stars, et cetera.
So this is a good place to go to, see if your packages legit, you should also click
through to the GitHub, check out the code if you want to.
So it's good practice to copy and paste this exact command.
There is a button right here that will help you do that.
If you make a typo and don't type in the correct package name, there have been known to
be typosquatters, right?
So packages with security vulnerability is that take advantage of people mis typing these
package names and then they'll go in install a malicious version of the library.
So there are some security considerations here.